VIVEK KUMAR

Z-385B, Sector-12, Noida, UP

Mobile: 9472952638

E-mail: vivekkrsd@gmail.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE

To work for an ambitious organization in a challenging and growth-oriented field, that would utilize my skills, experience and provide an exciting opportunity to work and learn new technologies in a dynamic engineering team environment.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Working as a PHP and Java developer at Exclusive-Or (XOR) Labs Pvt. Ltd. From January 18, 2016 to till date.

Worked as a Web developer at Douce Infotech Pvt. Ltd. from June 2013 to May 2014.

PROJECTS UNDERTAKEN

> Pensions management::

Duration: Dec, 2019 to till date.

Team Size: 5

Role Played: Developer

Skills Used: Laravel, JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, HTML, BootStrap

Description:

Pensions management Platform allows employers to register for their plan, add employees, and make contributions all through a single portal and login. Pensions & Benefits Platform streamlines and makes efficient the process of getting reporting and contribution dollars from the local church to the plan sponsor and the managing investment firm.

> Donation management:

Duration: July, 2018 to Nov, 2018.

Team Size: 10

D 1

Role Played: Developer

Skills Used: Laravel, JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, HTML, BootStrap.

Description:

All-In-One donation management platform combines unlimited online and mobile gift forms, text-to-give, tuition payments, crowdfunding and peer-to-peer fundraising, event registration, donor data and analytics into one cloud-based platform. All the tools you need to fund your mission, from one company, in one place.

> Real-time Infrastructure Monitor:

Duration: January, 2016 to June, 2017.

Team Size: 7

Role Played: Developer

Skills Used: Java, PHP, Shell Script, JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, HTML, CSS,

Linux Administration.

Description:

Real-time Infrastructure Monitor is an enterprise tool that provides a unified view for IT-systems monitoring. Through proactive, comprehensive and integrated monitoring and reporting, Real-time Infrastructure Monitor gives complete visibility and control over the availability, performance and capacity of your IT environment, from applications to servers and virtual machines, to network devices. Although comprehensive and scalable, Real-time Infrastructure Monitor is also easy to use and can be deployed in minutes.

> FabChat (Social Media)

Duration: Feb 3, 2015 to April 10, 2015.

Team Size: 1

Role Played: Designer, Developer & Tester

Skills Used: PHP, JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, HTML, CSS, MySQL, Hosting Administration.

Description:

FabChat is developed to provide the facility to share Image, text and get connected with others.

TECHNICAL SKILL

Languages : C, Java, Shell Script

Web Technologies : JSP, PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Framework : Laravel, Log4J

Database : MySQL, MS-SQL

Operating System : Windows 7/8/10, Red Hat, Ubuntu, Solaris

Tools : Eclipse, Intellij, Maven, SVN, Jenkins, PHPStrom, Git

EDUCATION

M.C.A from G.L Bajaj Institute of Technology and Management, Greater Noida in 2016 with First Division..

B.C.A from L.N. Mishra College of Business Management, Muzaffarpur in 2014 with First Division..

12th from V.R College, Bhagwanpur in 2011 with First Division.

10th from Prestine Children High School, Muzaffarpur in 2008 with Second Division.

CERTIFICATION, INTERNSHIP & TRAINING DETAILS

CMC Pvt. Limited, NOIDA: 3 Months training on J2EE.

STRENGTH

- ➤ Ability to adopt and learn new technologies.
- ➤ Ability to work in multi-cultural and multi-functional team environment.
- Enjoy facing the challenges of new situations, Hardworking & Dedication to Work.
- ➤ Confidence and Patience.
- > Friendly Nature.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Father's Name:Dilip Kumar SinghDate of Birth:October 31, 1993Languages Known:Hindi and English

Gender:MaleCivil Status:SingleReligion:HinduNationality:Indian

Hobby : Watching Movie.

Permanent Address : Bishnupur Chak Pahad, Sahebganj, Muzaffarpur,

Bihar Pin-843125

DECLARATION

I do hereby declare and confirm that all the above statements are true, complete and correct to the best of my knowledge. If selected, I shall do my work most conscientiously.

Date: Vivek Kumar